javascripture.com 2001-06-04

# LAUNCHBASE: Privacy Policy

**Monday, June 4th 2001**

**[Top](http://www.launchbase.net/) : Privacy Policy**

Launchbase Network is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our many offerings. This policy may change from time to time so please check back periodically. 

This policy will let you know: 

  1. [What personally identifiable information is collected from you](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#what); 
  2. [What cookies are and how they are used](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#cookies); 
  3. [How your information is used](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#how); 
  4. [Who is collecting your information](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#who); 
  5. [With whom your information may be shared](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#share); 
  6. [What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#choice); 
  7. [How you can access, update or delete your information](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#update); 
  8. [How Launchbase Network treats your personal financial and health-related information](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#financial); 
  9. [The kind of security precautions that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#security); 
  10. [How Launchbase Network protects children's privacy](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#kids); 
  11. [What else you should know about your online privacy.](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#else)
  12. [How to contact us for more information.](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#contact)

* * *

**NOTICE:[Click here](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/online/sitesee/index.html) for important information about safe surfing from the Federal Trade Commission.**

* * *

**What personally identifiable information does Launchbase Network collect from me?**

Launchbase Network collects information in several ways from different parts of our network of web sites. 

Some personal information is gathered when you register. During registration of some special services, Launchbase Network asks for your name, email address, birth date, gender, zip code, occupation, industry and personal interests. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once you register you are no longer anonymous to Launchbase Network - you are given a Launchbase Network ID and are able to take full advantage of Launchbase Network's many offerings. 

In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you submit a listing for a web site; and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. If you contact Launchbase Network we may keep a record of that correspondence. Launchbase Network also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. Wherever Launchbase Network collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

* * *

**What are cookies and how does Launchbase Network use them?**

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, Launchbase Network uses [cookies](http://www.zdwebopedia.com/cookie.htm) to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. All sites on Launchbase Network where you are prompted to log-in or that are customizable require that you accept cookies. (See ["What are my choices regarding collection, use and distribution of my information?"](http://www.launchbase.net/Privacy_Policy.htm#choice) for more information on cookies.) 

Generally, we use cookies to: 

  1. To store your zip code for other services, such as Yellow Pages, weather, movie times and local news. 
  2. Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing Launchbase Network is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior. 
  3. Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of Launchbase Network's network of web sites you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on Launchbase Network a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites.

Advertising networks that serve ads onto Launchbase Network may also use their own cookies. 

Launchbase Network also collects [IP addresses](http://www.zdwebopedia.com/TERM/I/IP_address.html) for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. In addition, Launchbase Network Mail includes IP addresses in outgoing mail message headers.

* * *

**How does Launchbase Network use my information?**

Launchbase Network's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our network of sites. This includes personalization services, interactive communications, online shopping and many other types of services, most of which are completely free to you. In order to provide services free of charge, we display advertisements. By knowing a little about you, Launchbase Network is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. 

In our role of delivering targeted advertisements, Launchbase Network plays the middleman. Advertisers give us an advertisement and tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, males over 35 years old). Launchbase Network takes the advertisement and displays it to users meeting that criteria. In this process, the advertiser never has access to individual account information. Only Launchbase Network has access to individuals' accounts. This kind of advertisement targeting is done with banner ads as well as promotional email through Launchbase Network Delivers. You will only receive special offers via email from Launchbase Network if you have indicated in your account preferences that you would like to receive them. You can change your account preferences at any time. 

Launchbase Network does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, during a promotion, from our server log files or from surveys. We do this to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. Launchbase Network may share this aggregated data with advertisers or business partners.

* * *

**Who is collecting information?**

When you are on a Launchbase Network site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Launchbase Network alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise.  If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than Launchbase Network, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. 

Please be aware that Launchbase Network advertisers or web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those web sites linked to Launchbase Network are not covered by this privacy policy.

* * *

**With whom does Launchbase Network share my information?**

As a general rule, Launchbase Network will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see the Terms of Service or Use Agreements for each of our products and services for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed. 

Merchants listed in Launchbase Network Shopping or site or in Launchbase Network Stores have separate privacy and data collection practices. Launchbase Network has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding the merchant, their store, and their privacy policies, return to that store's home page and click on their **Information** link. 

_Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate_: Under confidentiality agreements, Launchbase Network may match user information with third party data. Also, Launchbase Network discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. 

_Other:_ Launchbase Network may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Launchbase Network's [Terms of Service](http://www.launchbase.net/Terms_of_Use.htm) or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Launchbase Network's rights or property, other Launchbase Network users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Launchbase Network may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.

* * *

**What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**

Launchbase Network may, from time to time, send you email regarding our products and services. Only Launchbase Network  will send you these direct mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. 

On some types of Launchbase Network promotions, we will ask for your email address in order to update you on your score, entries, and status in prize drawings. When you participate in these types of promotions, you automatically receive promotion-related email, unless you choose the no-email option that some promotions offer. Occasionally these promotion-related email messages may include targeted advertisements. 

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those Launchbase Network services that require cookies to function properly. You can still use the majority of all Launchbase Services even if you do not accept cookies. 

Launchbase Network does not sell or rent user information to anyone. 

* * *

**What is Launchbase Network's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?** Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. 

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided. 

You can send email to [Support](http://www.launchbase.net/Support/)

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service. 

You can send email to [Support](http://www.launchbase.net/Support/)

 Residual information will remain within our archive records.

If you are participating in a Launchbase Network promotion and you wish to update your email address on the promotions mailing list or to quit a promotion and cease receiving promotion-related email, please [contact us](http://www.launchbase.net/Contact_Us.htm).

* * *

**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**

Whenever Launchbase Network handles personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, Launchbase Network takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant [Terms of Service](http://www.launchbase.net/Terms_of_Use.htm) and this Privacy Policy. All of our servers are housed in a secure environment under lock and key.  All personal information gathered is on a secure server in a directory inaccessible to the public.  Only the system administrator can access or edit the information. 

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Launchbase Network will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Also remember to sign out of your Launchbase Network account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Launchbase Network cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

* * *

**What about children's privacy?** Launchbase Network does NOT collect online contact information without prior parental consent or parental notification, which will include an opportunity for the parent to prevent use of the information and participation in the activity. Without prior parental consent, online information will only be used to respond directly to the child's request and will not be used for other purposes without prior parental consent. We do NOT collect personally identifiable offline contact information without prior parental consent. We do NOT distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information with out prior parental consent. We do NOT give the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information without prior parental consent. We do NOT entice by the prospect of a special game, prize or other activity, to divulge more information than is needed to participate in the activity.

* * *

**What else should I know about my privacy?**

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online.

* * *

**How to contact us for more information** If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact  Privacy Information  Launchbase Network, Inc.  PO Box 868  La Feria, TX 78559  [Email](http://www.launchbase.net/Contact_Us.htm)  

* * *

**Additional Information**

Questions regarding this statement should be [directed here](http://www.launchbase.net/Contact_Us.htm). 

**Also see...**

  * [Electronic Frontier Foundation](http://www.eff.org/) \- a civil liberties organization working to protect your rights online. 
  * [Electronic Privacy Information Center](http://epic.org/) \- established to focus public attention on emerging civil liberties issues relating to the National Information Infrastructure. 
  * [Privacy Issues Page](http://www.cdt.org/privacy/) \- from the Center for Democracy and Technology (CDT). 
  * [The EPIC Cookies Page](http://www.epic.org/privacy/internet/cookies/) \- definitions, links, and news. 
  * [How to Protect Your Privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html) \- information from the Federal Trade Commission.
